Guide to the J. Arthur (Jesse Arthur) Younger Papers, 1951-1968
Department of Special Collections
J. Arthur (Jesse Arthur) Younger Papers,
1951-1968
Special Collections M0190
Younger, J. Arthur (Jesse Arthur), 1893-1967.
12.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Restricted access: requires 24 hr. paging period.
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. J. Arthur Younger and Mr. and Mrs. Walter Robinson, Jr., 1968.
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
JESSE ARTHUR YOUNGER
1893. April 11. Born in Albany, Linn Co., Oregon. Moved to Kirkland, Washington.
1915. Graduated from the University of Washington at Seattle.
1917. Aug. Called into the Federal service with the Washington National Guard. Served overseas for 10 months with the 48th Coast Artillery Corps.
1919. June Discharged as a Captain.
1920-30. Vice-president, director, manager of mortgage loan dept. of the Seattle Title Trust Co.
1930-34 President, Seattle Mortgage Loan Co.
1934-37 Regional appraiser for the Home Owners Loan Corp., asst. appraiser adviser for Home Loan Bank Board. Chief of Savings & Loan Div. of Federal Home Loan Bank Board.
1937 Moved to San Mateo, Calif.
1937-52 Executive vice-president of Citizens Federal Savings & Loan Assn. in San Francisco.
1953-67 U. S. House of Representatives. 9th Congressional District, California. Republican.
1967. June 20. Died.
The J. Arthur Younger Papers represent virtually the complete written record of ten years in the House of Representatives (1954-1964). Almost every aspect of a Congressman's life and duties are covered: elections; House rules and procedure; committee activity; public and private bills; public opinion; contact with constituents; the extent of obligatory appearances at Washington and California events.
In organizing this collection, effort has been made, wherever possible, to maintain the filing system used by J. Arthur Younger. Congressman Younger's folder titles appear in this register as bold-type. Cross-references, which have been added for the convenience of the reader, appear in upper/lower case type.
KEY: The numbers at the right margin of each entry represent box and folder numbers. Hence, 2 - 23 indicates Box 2, Folder 23. 9 - 6/10 indicates that material on that subject may be found in Box 9, folders 6 through 10, inclusively.
CONTAINER LIST
- Academies, General -- Applications (For Constituents to Meet People). (Box 1)
- Applications for Job Appointments -- Bills, 84th Congress, Special (HR 232). (Box 2)
- Bills, 84th Congress, Special (HR 1548)-- Bills, 86th Congress, Special (HR 2485). (Box 3)
- Bills, 86th Congress, Special (HR 5675)-- Bills 87th Congress, Special (HR 1397). (Box 4)
- Bills, 87th Congress, Special (HR 1398) -- California, Water Problems. (Box 5)
- California State Government, Departments -- Civil Defense, General. (Box 6)
- Civil Rights, General -- Communism, General. (Box 7)
- Compensation -- Contracts, Government, General. (Box 8)
- Copyrights and Patents, 1964-65 --Field Office Memos, 1958-59. (Box 9)
- Field Office Memos, 1959-60 --Gifford, Geraldine. (Box 10)
- Government, General -- Inflation. (Box 11)
- Insurance, General -- Litton Industries. (Box 12)
- Mail Order Shipments -- Newsletter. (Box 13)
- Newspapers -- Political: Elections 1964(Congratulations). (Box 14)
- Political: Elections 1964(Senate) -- Pornography. (Box 15)
- Post Office, Department -- Post Offices, Westlake, 1954. (Box 16)
- Presidential Succession, 1964 --Redwood City Harbor, 1954 (April)- 1956 (Box 17)
- Redwood City Harbor, 1957-58 --Small Business Administration, 1955-57. (Box 18)
- Small Business Administration, 1963-64 --State Department, Amelia Earhart Story. (Box 19)
- State Department, Cases, 1955-56 --United Nations (Miscellaneous). (Box 20)
- United States Information Agency -- Veteran's Administration, V.A. Hospital in Palo Alto. (Box 21)
- Visitors -- Youth Symphony. (Box 22)
- Miscellaneous (Box 23)
- RESTRICTED (Box 24)
- Aandahl, Frederick G. (1897 -); asst. sec. of interior. (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Abell, Bess (). (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Academies, general; see also:
  - Air Force Academy
  - Military Academy (West Point)
  - Naval Academy
- ACADEMIES, GENERAL.
  - Class of 1956. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Class of 1957. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Class of 1958. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Adair, E. Ross (1907 -); Congressman, 4th. Ind. (Box 14, Folder 13, Box 15, Folder 8, Folder 12)
- Adams, Joseph P. (1907 -); lawyer, consultant. (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Adams, Sherman (1899 -); asst. to the President. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Adamson, Daniel, private bill. (Box 3, Folder 24)
- ADMINISTRATION, PUBLIC OPINION ON.
  - 1963 - 1964. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1965. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Agency For International Development (AID). (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Aging. (Box 15, Folder 32)
- AGRICULTURE.
  - General, 1955 - 1956. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General, 1955 - 1956. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General, 1963 - 1964. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General, 1965. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General, 1966. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Agriculture Yearbooks, 1960 - 1962. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Agriculture Yearbooks, 1962. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Air Force, Dept. of the; see also: (Box 9, Folder 6/10)
- AIR FORCE, DEPT. OF THE.
  - 1955 - 1957. (Box 1, Folder 13, Folder 14)
  - 1961 - 1963. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1965 - 1966. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Sonic Boom Study, 1957 - 1962. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- AIR FORCE ACADEMY.
  - 1954 - 1955. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1955 - 1956. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1956 - 1957. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1957 - 1958. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Air Pollution Control. (Box 5, Folder 21, Folder 33)
- Airline Certifications. (Box 2, Folder 35/6)
- AIRLINE PASS PRIVILEGES. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Airports. (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Alaska Good Friday Earthquake. (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Albastro, Arlene, private bill. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Albright, Faustina, private bill. (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Alger, Bruce R. (1918 -); Congressman, 5th Tex. (Box 13, Folder 6)
- ALCATRAZ ISLAND. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Allen, George V. (1903 -); Government official. (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Allen, John J., Jr. (1899 -); Government official. (Box 6, Folder 7, Box 15, Folder 12)
- Allen, Leo E. (1898 -); Congressman, 16th Ill. (Box 15, Folder 12)
- AMERICAN LEGION - 1966. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Andersen, H. Carl (1897 -); Congressman, 7th Minn. (Box 14, Folder 23)
- Andersen, Jack Z. (1914 -); Government official. (Box 22, Folder 15)
- Anderson, Webster (1906 -); Army officer. (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Andresen, August H. (). (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Andrews, Mark E. (1903 -); Lawyer and industrialist. (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Anslinger, Henry J. (1892 -); U.S. Comm. of narcotics. (Box 20, Folder 29)
- Antoneos, Stavroula (Private Bill). (Box 3, Folder 35)
- APPLICATIONS (FOR CONSTITUENTS TO MEET PEOPLE). (Box 1, Folder 28)
- APPLICATIONS FOR JOB APPOINTMENTS - FROM 1953.
  - A - C (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - D - K (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - L - N (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - O - Z (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Aramburu, Josefa (Private Bill) (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Arendo, Leslie C. (1895 -); Congressman, 17th Ill. (Box 14, Folder 31, Box 15, Folder 3, Box 22, Folder 22)
- Arias, Juan Reyes (Private Bill) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- ARMED SERVICES (Box 2, Folder 5, Folder 6)
- Armstrong, James Sinclair (1915 -); Government official (Box 12, Folder 22)
- ARMY:
  - 1955 - 1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1963 - 1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1965 - 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Misc. (Box 9, Folder 6, Folder 7, Folder 8, Folder 9, Folder 10)
- ARMY - ENGINEERS
  - Correspondence, 1955 - 1956 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Misc., 1955 - 1956 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Misc., 1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Misc., 1961 - 1962 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Misc., 1964 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Pacifica Breakwater (Box 2, Folder 18)
- ARMY - MENINGITIS, 1964 - 1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- ARNTSEN, MR. & MRS. E. B. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- ARTS - 1963 - 1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Aspinall, Wayne N. (1896 -); Congressman, 4th Colo. (Box 4, Folder 20)
- ASSASINATION OF PRES. KENNEDY (Box 2, Folder 21)
- ATOMIC ENERGY COMMISSION
  - 1963 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1955 - 1956 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - General (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Auchincloss, James C. (1885 -); Congressman, 3rd N.J. (Box 14, Folder 20, Box 15, Folder 12)
- AUTOGRAPHS - 1963 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- AUTOMOBILE SAFETY (SPECIAL MATERIAL COMMITTEE) (Box 2, Folder 27)
- AUTOMOTIVE (GENERAL) (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Avery, William H. (1911 -) Cong., 1st Kan. (Box 15, Folder 12)
- AVIATION
  - 1963 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 1965 - 1966 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Civil (Flower shippers) (Box 2, Folder 35, Folder 36)
  - General (Box 9, Folder 27, Folder 28)
- AWARDS, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Ayres, William H. (1916 -); Cong., 14th Ohio. (Box 14, Folder 31, Box 22, Folder 28)
- BACKDOOR SPENDING, 1963 - 1965 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Bahmeier, Carl E., Jr. (). (Box 17, Folder 20)
- Baird, Julian B. (1892 -); Government official (Box 20, Folder 30)
- Baker, Howard H. (1902 -); Congressman, 2nd Tenn. (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Baldwin, John F., Jr. (1915 -); Cong., 6th Cal. (Box 1, Folder 25, Box 5, Folder 36, Folder 39, Box 13, Folder 4, Folder 23, Box 15, Folder 12)
- Ball, Robert M. (1914 -); Social security spec. (Box 5, Folder 22, Box 9, Folder 23, Box 11, Folder 9, Box 10, Box 19, Folder 4, Folder 6)
- BANKING
  - 1963 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Currency - 1965 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Banks, Harvey O. () (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Bantz, F. A. () (Box 13, Folder 31)
- Bartlett, Edward L. (1904 -); Senator, Alaska (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Bates, William H. (1917 -); Cong., 6th Mass. (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Baughman, Urbanus E. (1905 -); Government official (Box 20, Folder 29)
- Bay Area Rapid Transit (BART) (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Beam, Jacob D. (1908 -); Ambassador to Poland (Box 3, Folder 13, Box 20, Folder 3)
- Beamer, John V. (1896 -); Government official (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Beau, Lucas V. (1895 -); AC officer (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Becker, Frank J. (1899 -); Cong., 3rd N.Y. (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Beek, Joseph A. () (Box 6, Folder 4, Folder 5)
- Belcher, Page (1899 -); Cong. 1st Okla. (Box 15, Folder 12)
- BeLieu, Kenneth E. ()
- Bell, Alphonzo () (Box 6, Folder 9, Box 15, Folder 18, Folder 10)
- Bell, Colin W. (1903 -); Organization exec.
- Bell, David S. () (Box 1, Folder 15, Box 18, Folder 13)
- Bender, C. R. (); Coast Guard (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Bender, George H. () (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Bennett, Charles E. (1910 -); Cong., 2nd Fla. (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Bentley, Alvin M. (1918 -); Cong. 8th Michigan (Box 3, Folder 32, Box 15, Folder 12)
- Berg, William M. () (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Berlin, Seymour S. () (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Berry, Ellis Y. (1902 -); Cong., 2nd S. Dak. (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Berry, Frank B. (1892 -); Government official (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Betts, Jackson E. (1904 -); Cong., 8th Ohio (Box 15, Folder 12)
- BILLS - 84TH CONGRESS, PERSONAL (Box 2, Folder 34)
- BILLS - 84TH CONGRESS, SPECIAL
  - HR 232 - Civil aeronautics, flower shippers (Box 2, Folder 35, Folder 36)
  - HR 1548 - Kuhn (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - HR 1549 - Carbon (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - HR 1550 - Lizardo (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - HR 1551 - Albastro (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - HR 1552 - Cruz (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - HR 1997 - San Filippo (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - HR 3197 - Neuman (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - HR 5953 - Hoff (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - HR 8178 - Small business administration (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - HR 8503 - Fisheries (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - HR 8935 - Sutter kin claim (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - HR 10,573 - Shipbuilding (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - HR 11,424 - Czech claims (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - HR 11,619 - Narcotics (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence during - du Planty (Box 3, Folder 15)
- BILLS - 85TH CONGRESS, PUBLIC
  - HR 1016 - Czech claims fund (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - HR 1017 - Civ. Aeronautics Act Amdmt. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - HR 1020 - Lincoln's Birthday (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - HR 1021 - War claims vs. Germany & Japan (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - HR 1023 - HR - 1028 - Flood Control (Box 3, Folder 20, Folder 21)
  - HR 1278 - Geo. Washington as Gen. of armies (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - HR 6273 - Legis. reorg. Act (Box 3, Folder 23)
- BILLS - 85TH CONGRESS, SPECIAL
  - HR 1868 - Adamson (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - HR 1873 - King (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - HR 1875 - Liera (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - HR 1876 - Rousos (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - HR 4352 - Spoto (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - HR 7293 - Dykeman (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - HR 7754 - Albright (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - HR 9201 - Marshall (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - HR 11,840 - Czech claims (Box 3, Folder 32)
- BILLS - 86TH CONGRESS, SPECIAL
  - HR 1391 - Amdmt. for Robert Tarver (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - HR 2004 - Hawaii statehood (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - HR 1757 - Antones (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - HR 1758 - Cooley (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - HR 1760 - Demetrakopoulos (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - HR 1761 - Aramburu (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - HR 2485 - War claims (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - HR 5675 - Equal time (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - HR 5760 - War claims #2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - HR 9447 - Landesen (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - HR 9482 - Hsu, Jen (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - HR 10,232 - Sifuentes (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - HR 10,742 - Yamaguchi (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - HR 12,652 - Freitas (Box 4, Folder 7)
- BILLS - 87TH CONGRESS, PUBLIC
  - HR 51 - Cong. Fiscal Org. Comm. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - HR 52 - Residences for pages (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - HR 273 - Oppos. Red China in U. N. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- BILLS - 87TH CONGRESS, SPECIAL
  - HR 596 - Movement of defense materials (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - HR 1111 - Czechoslovakian claims (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - HR 1112 - Create foreign service academy (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - HR 1113 - Life ins. to cover est. liability for Fed estate tax (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - HR 1114 - Amdmt. sec. 4 of Fed. Home Loan Bank Act (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - HR 1115 - Postal salaries (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - HR 1116 - Limitation of payments to farmers (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - HR 1117 - War claims (WW II) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - HR 1118 - Fees for regulatory agencies (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - HR 1119 - Golden Gate National Cemetary (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - HR 1120 - Fed. Aviation Act Amdmt. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - HR 1122 - Air freight forwarder (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - HR 1123 - Stock distributions, non-recognition of gain or loss (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - HR 1124 - Stamp tax (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - HR 1125 - Urbiculture Dept. (Box 4, Folder 25, Folder 26)
  - HR 1126 - Dept of Transportation and Comm. (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - HR 1127 - Surplus property for park and rec. purposes (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - HR 1128 - Rapid Transit, S. F. Bay (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - HR 1241 - CAA Amendment (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - HR 1242 - Air transport. requirements (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - HR 1243 - Return address requirements (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - HR 1244 - Cong. payroll simplification (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - HR 1245 - Members' stationery allowance (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - HR 1397 - Arthur Tindell claims (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - HR 1398 - Juan Reyes Arias (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - HR 1399 - Josefa Pidlaon (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - HR 1474 - Ngoon Kim Kung (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - HR 1475 - Oliva del Rio (Vincenza) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - HR 1476 - Oliva del Rio (Rosetta) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - HR 1477 - [UNK] Rinehart
  - HR 1478 - Mark claims bill (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - HR 1479 - Ouchi (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - HR 2690 - Kotake (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - HR 3147 - Holtzer (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - HR 3506 - Fu (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - HR 5187 - Muzzi (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - HR 7071 - Advance officers on retired list w/o affecting pay (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - HR 9716 - Fujii (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - HR 9717 - Margetich (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - HR 9964 - Montara San. Dist. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - HR 10,090 - Stiletto (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - HR 10,275 - Cleal (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - HR 10,681 - Cert. Empl. S. F. Nav. Shipyard (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - HR 11,556 - Granucci (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - HR 12,559 - Miss Esther Mao (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 21)
- BIRNIE, MRS. REGINE (Box 5, Folder 22)
- BIRTH CERTIFICATES (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Blake, Ralph J. () (Box 5, Folder 13, Box 20, Folder 5)
- Bliss, Ray C. (1902 -); Member Rep. Nat. Comm. (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Boklen, Charles E. (1904 -); Government official (Box 1, Folder 28, Box 12, Folder 16, Box 19, Folder 22)
- Bolten, Frances P. (1885 -); Cong., 22n d Ohio (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Bonner, Herbert C. (1895 -); Cong. 1st N. C.
- BOOKS, GENERAL, 1963 - 1965 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Bosch, Albert H. (1908 -); Cong., 5th N. Y. (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Bowman, Joseph M. () (Box 20, Folder 21)
- BOY SCOUTS, GENERAL, 1963 - 1965 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Boyd, Alan J. () (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Boye, F. W., Jr. () (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Braderman, Eugene M. ()
- Bradford, Robert B. () (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Brantt, Karl () (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Brennan, Joseph R. () (Box 14, Folder 27)
- Brenner, Edward J. () (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Briggs, Richard W. () (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Brockett, W. A. () (Box 8, Folder 21, Folder 22)
- Brooks, Jack B. (1922 -); Cong., 2nd Tex. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Brooks, Overton (1897 -); Cong., 4th La. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Brown, Clarence J. (1893 -); Cong., 7th Ohio (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Brown, Edmund G. (1905 -); Gov. of Cal. (Box 2, Folder 30, Box 5, Folder 45)
- Brownstein, P. N. () (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Broyhill, Joel T. (1919 -); Cong., 10th Va. (Box 11, Folder 16, Box 15, Folder 12)
- Bruce, David (1898 -); Ambassador (Box 1, Folder 28, Box 12, Folder 16)
- Bruce, Donald () (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Bryan, Blackshear M. Jr. (1900 -); Army officer (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Bryant, Floyd S. (1894 -); Business exec. (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Buchanan, John H. Jr. () (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Buckley, Carper W. () (Box 12, Folder 32)
- Buckley, Charles A. (1890 -); Cong., 25th N. Y. (Box 3, Folder 21, Box 14, Folder 27)
- Budge, Homer H. (1910 -); Cong., 2nd Idaho (Box 14, Folder 23, Box 15, Folder 12)
- BUDGET, BUREAU OF, 1955 - 1956 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- BUDGET, CORRESPONDENCE
  - 1959 - 1960 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - to July 7, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - 1965 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Buland, George L. (1897 -); Lawyer (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Bunker, Ellsworth (1894 -); Ambassador to India (Box 17, Folder 28)
- Burch, Dean () (Box 14, Folder 30, Folder 31)
- Burgess, Carter L. (1916 -); Corp. exec. (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Burgess, Robert W. (1887 -); Statistician (Box 7, Folder 16, Folder 17)
- BURIALS, GENERAL (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Burns, James M. (1918 -); Political scientist (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Bush, Alvin R. (1893 -); Cong., 15th Pa. (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Business, small (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Button, A. Ronald (1903 -); Cal. state treasurer (Box 22, Folder 25)
- Byrnes, John W. (1913 -); Cong., 8th Wis. (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Cahill, William T. (1912 -); Cong., 1st N. J. (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Cale, Edward G. (1906 -); Govt. official (Box 19, Folder 20)
- CALIFORNIA, GENERAL FILE
  - 1955 - 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - 1958 - 1960 (1) (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - 1958 - 1960 (2) (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - 1962 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - 1963 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - 1964 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - 1965 - 1966 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - 1966, April to Dec. (Box 5, Folder 38)
- CALIFORNIA, BAY FILL AND SAN LUIS DRAIN (Box 5, Folder 39)
- CALIFORNIA, CHAMBER OF COMMERCE (Box 5, Folder 40)
- CALIFORNIA, INDUSTRIAL RELATIONS, LABOR STAT. (Box 5, Folder 41)
- CALIFORNIA, REAPPORTIONMENT (Box 5, Folder 42)
- CALIFORNIA, REPUBLICAN PARTY STATE CONVENTION (Box 5, Folder 43)
- CALIFORNIA, SHIPPING (Box 5, Folder 44)
- CALIFORNIA, WATER PROBLEMS (Box 5, Folder 45)
- CALIFORNIA STATE GOVT., DEPTS.
  - 1956 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1959 - 1960 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- CALIFORNIA STATE GOVT., LEGISLATURE (Box 6, Folder 4, Folder 5)
- CALIFORNIA STATE SOCIETY
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Knowland dinner (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 4/29/58dinner (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 1963 - 1964 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 1965 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- CALIFORNIA IN CONGRESS - EXCERPTS OF SPEECH (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Campbell, Joseph (1904 -); Educator, author (Box 7, Folder 6, Folder 18, Box 8, Folder 21, Box 10, Folder 24, Box 15, Box 16, Box 20, Folder 28, Folder 29)
- Canfield, Gordon (1898 -); Cong., 8th N. J. (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Cannon, Clarence (1879 -); Cong., 9th Mo. (Box 14, Folder 23)
- Carbon, Salvacion (Private bill) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- CARLANDER, CECIL (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Carlson, Delman Richard (1918 -); Fgn. Serv. ofcl. (Box 20, Folder 1, Folder 31)
- Carmichael, Arthur C. () (Box 16, Folder 29)
- Cartwright, Robert F. (1907 -); Fgn Serv. ofcl. (Box 5, Folder 1, Box 20, Folder 4)
- Carver, John A. Jr. () (Box 12, Folder 4, Box 17)
- Cassidy, William F. () (Box 2, Folder 14, Folder 16)
- Celebrezze, Anthony J. (1910 -); Mayor of Cleveland (Box 14, Folder 31)
- Celler, Emanuel (1888 -); Cong., 11th N.Y. (Box 2, Folder 34, Box 3, Folder 1, Folder 2, Folder 3, Folder 4, Folder 5, Folder 6, Folder 7, Folder 8, Folder 18, Folder 24, Folder 25, Folder 26, Folder 27, Folder 28, Folder 30, Folder 31, Folder 35, Folder 37, Folder 38, Box 5, Box 20)
- CEMETERIES, NATIONAL, 1963 - 1966 (Box 4, Folder 20, Box 6, Folder 14)
- CENSUS, GENERAL FILE, 1963 - 1966 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Chamberlain, Charles E. (1917 -); Cong. (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Charyk, Joseph V. (1920 -); Aero. scientist (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Chase, Jackson B. () (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Chenowith, J. Edgar (1897 -); Cong., 3rd Colo. (Box 15, Folder 12)
- China (Mainland), admission to the U. N. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Christopher, George (1907 -); Mayor of S.F. (Box 6, Folder 19, Box 11, Folder 24, Box 15, Folder 7, Box 18, Folder 12)
- Church, Marguerite S. (1892 -); Cong., 13th Ill. (Box 15, Folder 12)
- CIVIL AERONAUTICS ADMINISTRATION, 1956 - 1958 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Civil Aeronautics, flower shippers (Box 2, Folder 35, Folder 36, Box 3, Folder 17, Box 4, Folder 30)
- CIVIL AERONAUTICS BOARD, GENERAL
  - 1955 - 1956 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - 1957 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - 1959 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - 1965 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- CIVIL AERONAUTICS BOARD, AIRLINES, ADDITIONAL SERV. (Box 6, Folder 21)
- CIVIL AERONAUTICS BOARD, PLANE ACCIDENTS (Box 6, Folder 23)
- CIVIL AERONAUTICS BOARD, PLANE INSPECTION (Box 6, Folder 24)
- CIVIL DEFENSE ADMINISTRATION, CORR., 1955 - 1956 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- CIVIL DEFENSE, GENERAL
  - 1963 - 1964 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - 1966 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- CIVIL RIGHTS, GENERAL
  - 1963 - 1964 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1965 - 1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- CIVIL SERVICE, CASES
  - 1956 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 1957 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- CIVIL SERVICE COMMISSION
  - 1955 - 1956 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 1959 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- CIVIL SERVICE, GENERAL
  - 1955 - 1956 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1957 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1963 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1964 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 1966 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- CIVIL SERVICE, PLANNERS, ESTIMATORS & CONGRESSMEN (Box 7, Folder 13)
- CIVIL SERVICE - STALZER, WILLIAM J. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Clawson, Del () (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Clay, Henry J. (1915 -); Lawyer (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Clemens, Cyril () (Box 3, Folder 22, Box 4, Folder 25)
- Clevenger, Cliff () (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Clifton, J. Hart () (Box 12, Folder 28)
- COAST GUARD, 1964 - 1965 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Cole, Albert L. (1894 -); Mag. publisher (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Cole, Albert M. (1901 -); Corp. exec. (Box 2, Folder 3, Folder 4, Box 11, Folder 20)
- Collier, Harold R. (1915 -); Cong., 10th Ill. (Box 15, Folder 3)
- COMMERCE
  - Corres., 1955 - 1956 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Corres., 1957 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Misc., 1955 - 1956 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - General, 1965 - 1966 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- COMMITTEES
  - Interstate (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - General (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Joint on organization of Congress (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Joint economics (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Rules, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Statements before (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Unamerican activities, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- COMMONWEALTH CLUB OF CALIFORNIA (Box 7, Folder 27)
- COMMUNICATIONS, FCC
  - 1955 - 1956 (Box 7, Folder 28)